Guide to the Bangs Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Entries for 1941 contain reviews of Bangs's biography of his father, as well as his complaints about his dismissal from the faculty of Avon Old School for "teaching atheism." A letter of June 10 to Bernhard Knollenberg of the Yale library discusses Bangs's gift of Archibald MacLeish letters to Yale and his annotations for many of these letters. Subsequent letters to family and friends and to Yale discuss this project. An August 14 letter from MacLeish comments on restrictions placed on the letters. The scrapbook for 1942 includes an exchange of letters with Herman Hagedorn on Bangs's recollections of young poet John Magee, whom he had taught at Avon. (See especially letters of February 6, March 20, May 20, and May 25.)
In 1949 and early 1950 Bangs served as personal secretary to Julia Ellsworth Ford, and many of his diary entries and letters in the scrapbooks for these years record her activities in the last years of her life. The scrapbook for 1952 contains a copy of Bangs's article, "Julia Ellsworth Ford: An Appreciation" (p. 59). Letters and diary entries at this time also include Bangs's observations on the wealthy socialites of Miami and Palm Beach. A letter to Harrison Smith of October 5, 1951 recalls several anecdotes about Sinclair Lewis' visit to Ogunquit in 1939.
After Bangs's marriage in 1952 to Dorothy Barney, the entries in the scrapbooks become increasingly more sparse. An exchange of letters between Bangs and American literature bibliographer Jacob Blanck in March and April, 1955 reveals much information on the publications of John Kendrick Bangs, as do letters of March 28 and April 18 to the H. W. Wilson Company. The scrapbooks from 1957 to Bangs's death in 1964 consist mainly of exchanges of letters with numerous friends, with occasional news clippings and travel pictures or brochures.
Series VI, Writings (Boxes 47-52) consists mainly of research material, notes, and drafts for John Kendrick Bangs, Humorist of the Nineties. The Shorter Works subseries includes a short reminiscence of turn-of-the-century Ogunquit; Bangs's unpublished "Notes Toward a Theory of Poetry"; a ledger of miscellaneous thoughts on literature, religion, philosophy, and love which Bangs apparently intended for a never-completed autobiography under the name "John Fust"; and a collection of his newspaper articles and editorials for the Wells-Ogunquit Compass for 1933-35.
Series VII, Correspondence (Box 53), contains both business and personal letters to and from Bangs between 1919 and 1963. The file for Lawrence Mason, a friend and one of Bangs's instructors at Yale, contains two letters to Mason from publisher Thomas B. Mosher on his press's publications and a series of lengthy letters from Mason to Bangs from 1917-19 discussing literature, philosophy, politics, the war, and other matters. The file also includes a letter to Mason from Archibald MacLeish on January 19, 1916, revealing his debt to Mason's instruction at Yale ("You lured us into a sky our dreams had tempted with half-fearful wings... .") and predicting his own literary future: "I do not now expect, as I once did, laurel and thorn. No doubt a rose in the dust is the highest & lowest of this earths offerings. But the star is the same and the impulse the same whether the road is a sheep path in the valley or a great leap upward of the sheer rock." MacLeish also comments on John Masefield and includes an untitled short poem.
Series VIII, Personal Papers (Boxes 53-55), consists of clippings, pamphlets and brochures, and various legal papers relating to Francis Hyde Bangs's life and career, arranged alphabetically by subject, author, or title. Included are biographical information, yearbook and literary publications from Bangs's years at St. Paul's School (1909-11), notes and research material used in teaching, a bust of Bangs by the sculptor Anna Glenny Dunbar, and legal papers relating to his divorce from Geraldine Hall Bangs and to the estate of his brother John Kendrick Bangs, Jr.
Series IX., Photographs (Boxes 57-59) is divided into "People" and "Places" and contains photographs of Bangs and his family and friends, photographs by Danford Barney and James McKeldin, and scenes of Ogunquit, Maine and the Bangs home there. There are five folders of pictures of Bangs himself, photos and caricatures of John Kendrick Bangs, and several early photos of other members of the Bangs family, including two tintypes and an interesting photograph transferred to porcelain.
Oversize material (Box 60) contains larger items from the photograph series.
American literature; American periodicals; American wit and humor; Fiction -- Authorship; Humorous poetry; Lectures and lecturing; Literature, Modern -- 19th century; Literature, Modern -- 20th Century; Poetry -- Authorship; Popular literature; Cuba -- History; New York (N.Y.) -- Social life and customs; Ogunquit (Me.) -- History; Diaries; Scrapbooks; Authors; Editors; Humorists; Lecturers; Novelists; Poets; Alden, Henry Mills, 1836-1919; Bacheller, Irving, 1859-1950; Bangs, Francis Hyde, 1892-; Bangs, John Kendrick, 1862-1922; Bangs, Nathan, 1778-1862; Barney, Danford, 1892-1952; Daly, Augustin, 1838-1899; Erskine, John, 1879-1951; Gibson, Charles Dana, 1867-1944; Grant, Robert, 1852-1940; Harding, Warren G. (Warren Gamaliel), 1865-1923; Herford, Oliver, 1863-1935; Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920; Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1850-1924; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982; Markham, Edwin, 1852-1940; Martin, Edward Sandford, 1856-1939; Mason, Lawrence, 1882-1939; Parker, Gilbert, 1862-1932; Peck, Harry Thurston, 1856-1914; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919; Root, Elihu, 1845-1937; Russell, Lillian, 1861-1922; Van Dyke, Henry, 1852-1933; Warner, Charles Dudley, 1829-1900; Wood, Leonard, 1860-1927; Columbia University; Harper & Brothers; Yale College (1887- ). Class of 1915
- Scrapbooks, 1881-1917; Series I; 3.5' (8 boxes)
  - Scrapbooks (college clippings), 1881-84 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - Scrapbooks, 1887-96 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
  - Scrapbooks, 1896-99 (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
  - Scrapbook, 1899-1902 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook (drama), 1901-02 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 9)
  - Ledger, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook (with diary entries), 1907-08 (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
  - Scrapbook (with diary entries and accounts), 1909 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Scrapbooks, 1910-11 (Box 6, Folder 14-15)
  - Scrapbooks, 1912-14 (Box 7, Folder 16-18)
  - Scrapbooks, 1916-17 (Box 8, Folder 19-20)
  - Scrapbook, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 20a)
    Scope and Contents
    Stamped on cover: "Clara M. Owen"
- Writings, 1888-1921; Series II; 4.0' (9 boxes)
  Series II, Writings (Boxes 9-17), consists of manuscript and printed copies of novels, short stories, articles, and poems of John Kendrick Bangs. For Shorter Works, the published copy is indicated unless otherwise noted.
  - BOOKS AND PLAYS
    - The Genial Idiot
      - Typescript, corrected ("He Writes a Detective Story"), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 21)
      - Printed copy (in scrapbook), 1903 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - In Camp With a Soldier
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 23-24)
    - The Inventions of the Idiot
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 25-26)
    - Katharine
      - Holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 27-28)
      - Program, 1888 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Lady Teazle
      - Lyrics: holograph and typescript (Box 9, Folder 30)
      - Programs, announcements, and reviews (scrapbook), 1904-05 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - New Waggings of Old Tales
      - Reviews, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - A Rebellious Heroine
      - Harper's New Monthly Magazine (incomplete), [1896 Jun] (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Toppleton's Client
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 34-35)
    - Uncle Sam, Trustee
      - Announcements, reviews, photos (scrapbook), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - SHORT STORIES AND SKETCHES
    - "An Adventure with a Cabman." New York Herald, 1904 Jan 24 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - "The Adventures of Bobby Faxon: Comedian." The Reader's Magazine, 1912 Jun 2 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - "Alice in Stageland": scrapbook (with "Jimmieboy in Trustland" (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - "Amalgamated Mary Ann." Success Magazine, 1909 Mar (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - "An Astral Christmas." Sunday Magazine, 1906 Dec 23 (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - "The Annals of the P. O. Club"
    - "Something of a Blow." New York Herald, 1908 Dec 6 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Illustrated Sunday Magazine, 1909-11 (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - "As to Transfer Poetry." New York Herald, 1904 Jan 31 (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - "Being a Ghost." Life, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - "The Biter Bit." The Smart Set, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - "The Bookworm--in Trouble Again." New York Herald, 1904 Feb 14 (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - "Bowdoin's Proposal." Sunday Magazine, 1909 Dec 19 (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - "A Chat with Father Time." New York Herald, 1903 Dec 27 (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - "A Chat with George Washington." New York Herald, 1904 Feb 21 (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - "The Complete After-Dinner Speaker." New York Herald, 1904 Jan 17 (Box 11, Folder 51)
    - "A Delegate of Destiny." Ainslee's, 1909 Feb (Box 11, Folder 52)
    - "Don Giovanni Comes to America." New York Herald, 1904 Jan 10 (Box 11, Folder 53)
    - "The Double Revenge of Hawkesworth." The Metropolitan Magazine, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 54)
    - "The Exploits of Raffles Holmes." New York Herald, 1908 Nov 1 (Box 11, Folder 55)
    - "From Chum to Chum." Harper's, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 56)
    - "The Gallery God on Musical Comedy and Critics", 1904 Feb 7 (Box 11, Folder 57)
    - "The Ghost of M'Fadden." Milwaukee Sentinel, 1908 Feb 2 (Box 11, Folder 58)
    - "The Great Day When Matilda Voted." The Ladies' Home Journal, 1910 Aug (Box 11, Folder 59)
    - Harper's Weekly: miscellaneous sketches, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 60-61)
    - "The Idiot on Broadway." Broadway Magazine, 1907 (Box 11, Folder 62)
    - "Imaginary Recollections of Wilberforce Jenkins, Esq." Illustrated Sunday Magazine (Box 11, Folder 63)
    - "Interludes." Harper's Weekly, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 64-65)
    - "Jimmieboy in Trust Land": galley proofs (incomplete), 1905 (Box 12, Folder 66)
    - "Jimmieboy's Tool Chest: A Tale of Christmas Night", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 67)
    - "John Kendrick Bangs Presents the Genial Philosopher." The Independent, 1916 May 29 (Box 12, Folder 68)
    - "The Landing of Danny Wells." Munsey's Magazine (Box 12, Folder 69)
    - "The Last Night", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 70)
    - "A Locked-Out Santa Claus." New York Herald, 1907 Dec 15 (Box 12, Folder 71)
    - "Lost and Found." Golden Book, 1929 Apr (Box 12, Folder 72)
    - "Love Letters of A. Noodle, Esq." (incomplete), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 73)
    - "Lucky?" Illustrated Sunday Magazine, 1911 Oct 29 (Box 12, Folder 74)
    - "The Magnanimity of Billups", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 75)
    - "A Marriage in High Statuary Life." New York Herald, 1908 Feb 23 (Box 12, Folder 76)
    - "Mr. Billups Reads Brother Roosevelt's First Article", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 77)
    - "Mrs. Upton's Device." Harper's New Monthly Magazine, 1897 Oct (Box 12, Folder 78)
    - "Monsieur Rousseau", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 79)
    - "Nancy Jane"
      Related Archival Materials note
      See: "Uncle Jedediah on Motoring"
    - "Neglected Conversations." Harper's Monthly Magazine", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 80)
    - "The Nemesis of Whitington." The Metropolitan Magazine, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 81)
    - "On the Links with Francis Wilson." Harper's Weekly (incomplete), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 82)
    - "Over the Wire": [Illustrated] Sunday Magazine, 1908 Dec 13 (Box 12, Folder 83)
    - "Pepper and Salt." Illustrated Sunday Magazine, 1910-11 (Box 12, Folder 84)
    - "The Periwinkle Papers": printed copy, corrected (in notebooks). [Harper's Young People], [1894?] (Box 12, Folder 85)
    - "Prince Henry's Diary." New York Herald, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 86)
    - "A Proposal Under Difficulties." Harper's New Monthly Magazine, 1895 Jun (Box 12, Folder 87)
    - The Rambler, 1916 Dec (Box 12, Folder 87a)
    - "The Reformers." Harper's Weekly, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 88)
    - "Resuscitation of Santa Claus." Sunday Magazine, 1914 Dec 20 (Box 12, Folder 89)
    - "Saint Valentine Comes to Town on Business." New York Herald, 1908 Feb 9 (Box 12, Folder 90)
    - "The Smartness of Alexander." The Housekeeper, 1907 Sep (Box 12, Folder 91)
    - "The Social Savings-Bank." Harper's Bazaar, 1910 Dec (Box 12, Folder 92)
    - "Some Reminiscences of Wm. Dawson, Amateur." New York Herald, 1906 Jun 24 (Box 12, Folder 93)
    - "The Spectrophone." New York Herald (in notebook), 1904 (Box 12, Folder 94)
    - "A Strenuous Day at Oyster Bay": typescript, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 95)
    - "A Student of Sociology." Sunday Magazine, 1909 Jun 18 (Box 12, Folder 96)
    - "Table D'Hôte Talks" ( Harper's Weekly )
      - "In Old Madiera", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 97)
      - "The King of the Azores", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 98)
      - "The Mystery of Venice", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 99)
    - "Teddy in Blunderland" (in notebook), [1904?] (Box 12, Folder 100)
    - "That Little Dinner at Larrabee's", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 101)
    - "Tragedy of the Rejected Suitor." New York Herald, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 102)
    - "A Trustee for Santa Claus." New York Herald, 1901 Dec (Box 13, Folder 103)
    - "The Unclaimed Olives." The Illustrated Sunday Magazine, 1907 Oct 20 (Box 13, Folder 104)
    - "Uncle Jedediah on Motoring." (with "Nancy Jane") Harper's Weekly, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 105)
    - "A Venetian Day." New York Herald, 1908 Aug 16 (Box 13, Folder 106)
    - "The Verdict." Harper's Bazaar, 1912 May (Box 13, Folder 107)
    - "The Views and Reviews of the Idiot"
      - Holograph manuscript, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 108)
      - Illustrated Sunday Magazine (Box 13, Folder 109)
    - "Walnuts and Wine": printed copy (Box 13, Folder 110)
    - "A Weekend with Farringate." Sunday Magazine, 1913 Nov 23 (Box 13, Folder 111)
    - "Who's What and Why in America." New York Herald (in scrapbook), [1902] (Box 13, Folder 112)
    - "Who's Who in Wagner." The Smart Set, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 113)
    - "Yule College" (in copy of Labor, Cheer, and Love ) (Box 13, Folder 114)
    - Miscellaneous short fiction, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 115)
    - Illustrations, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 116)
  - ARTICLES AND ESSAYS
    - Columbia College Address (Twenty-fifth reunion of class of 1883), 1908 (Box 13, Folder 117)
    - "Confidential Communication." The Bookman, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 118)
    - Drama articles: Harper's Weekly, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 119-21)
    - "The Evolution of the Humorist": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 122)
    - "The Funeral of President McKinley", 1901 (Box 13, Folder 123)
    - "In Defense of Old Jokes." The Bookman, 1920 Sep (Box 13, Folder 124)
    - "The Incorrigible Optimist", 1920 Nov (Box 13, Folder 125)
    - "John Kendrick Bangs on Our Reconstruction of France." Boston Evening Transcript, 1918 Jun 15 (Box 14, Folder 126)
    - "Literary Notes." Harper's Magazine, 1898-99 (Box 14, Folder 127-28)
    - "Message to the Graduating Class of Public School 188", 1913 (Box 14, Folder 129)
    - "My House, Designed by My Neighbors." Suburban Life, 1908 Oct (Box 14, Folder 130)
    - "The Observer." New England Craftsman (Box 14, Folder 131)
    - "Platform Friendships": III. "Friendly Contacts": galley proof, 1915 Jan 28 (Box 14, Folder 132)
    - The Podmore Letters. Chap-Book, 1898 Jan-Jul (Box 14, Folder 133)
    - "Self-Assertion--A National Need", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 134)
    - "A Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Dead Authors": holograph manuscript, [1911?] (Box 14, Folder 135)
    - "Why Our Boys Over There Need Smokes." New York Sun, 1918 Jan 30 (Box 14, Folder 136)
    - "Why People Should Own and Read Books." (Box 14, Folder 137)
    - "Why We Laugh--Boris Sidis on the Psychology of It." Literary Digest, 1913 Nov 22 (Box 14, Folder 138)
    - "A Word Concerning American Humor." The Book Buyer (with John Corkin, "John Kendrick Bangs") (Box 14, Folder 139)
    - Letters to the Editor, 1918-21 (Box 14, Folder 140)
  - POETRY
    - "Follette de Billion" poems. Harper's Bazaar and Harper's Weekly (Box 14, Folder 141)
    - "A Line O' Cheer Each Day O' the Year"
      - Proof sheets, 1921-22 (Box 14, Folder 142-48)
      - Printed copies, 1921 Jan 1-7 (Box 14, Folder 149)
    - "Quatrains: Bookish, Wise and Otherwise": holograph notebook (Box 15, Folder 150)
    - "Random Rhymes" ("Sundry Rhymes"): typescripts and printed copies, 1900 (Box 15, Folder 151)
    - "To F. Hopkinson Smith": typescript, corrected, 1910 (Box 15, Folder 152)
    - "A Line a Day" Book: holograph notebook, 1908 (Box 15, Folder 153)
    - "A Line a Day" Book: holograph notebook, 1914-15 (Box 15, Folder 154)
    - "A Line a Day" Book: holograph notebook, 1916-17 (Box 15, Folder 155)
    - "A Line a Day" Book: holograph notebook, 1918 (Box 16, Folder 156)
    - "A Line a Day" Book: holograph notebook, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 157)
    - Poetry scrapbook (clippings), 1905-07 (Box 16, Folder 158)
    - Poetry scrapbooks (clippings), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 159-60)
    - Miscellaneous poems: holograph and typescript, 1909-19, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 161)
    - Miscellaneous poems: printed copies, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 162-63)
- Correspondence, 1887-1922; Series III; 0.5' (1 box)
  Series III, Correspondence (Box 18), is arranged alphabetically. Significant John Kendrick Bangs correspondents or those with five or more letters are given individual files; others are placed in "Letter" general files.
  - "A" general, 1887-1916, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 164)
  - Alden, Henry M., 1888 Apr 7 (Box 18, Folder 165)
  - American Committee for Devastated France, 1918-19 (Box 18, Folder 166)
  - "B" general, 1899-1919 (Box 18, Folder 167)
  - Bacheller, Irving, 1911-15 (Box 18, Folder 168)
  - Bangs, A. F. Bangs, F. N., 1867, 1885 (Box 18, Folder 169)
  - "C" general, 1900-20 (Box 18, Folder 170)
  - "D" general, 1897-1915 (Box 18, Folder 171)
  - Daly, Augustin, 1888-99 (Box 18, Folder 172)
  - Erskine, John, 1921 Mar 9 (Box 18, Folder 173)
  - "F" general, 1899-1906 (Box 18, Folder 174)
  - "G" general, 1900-02 (Box 18, Folder 175)
  - Gibson, Charles Dana [?], 1895, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 176)
  - Grant, Robert, 1897-1916 (Box 18, Folder 177)
  - "H" general, 1902-16 (Box 18, Folder 178)
  - Harding, Warren G. (with copy of "Why I Am For Harding"), 1920-21 (Box 18, Folder 179)
  - Herford, Oliver, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 180)
  - Howells, William Dean, 1897, 1911 (Box 18, Folder 181)
  - "J" general, 1915-18, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 182)
  - Johnson, Robert Underwood, 1918 (Box 18, Folder 183)
  - "K-L" general, 1889-1904 (Box 18, Folder 184)
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1900, 1902 (Box 18, Folder 185)
  - "M" general, 1894-1921 (Box 18, Folder 186)
  - McVicker, H. W. (with sketches), 1895 May 3 (Box 18, Folder 187)
  - Markham, Edwin, 1901, 1903 (Box 18, Folder 188)
  - Martin, Edward S., 1883, 1888 (Box 18, Folder 189)
  - "N" general, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 190)
  - Opper, Frederick B., 1931, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 191)
  - "P" general, 1889 (Box 18, Folder 192)
  - Parker, Gilbert, 1915-16 (Box 18, Folder 193)
  - Peck, Harry Thurston, 1912 (Box 18, Folder 194)
  - "R" general, 1884-1910 (Box 18, Folder 195)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1900-18 (Box 18, Folder 196)
  - Root, Elihu, 1900-19 (Box 18, Folder 197)
  - Russell, Lillian, 1905 (Box 18, Folder 198)
  - "S" general, 1887-1919 (Box 18, Folder 199)
  - Sherman, F. D., 1883-1909 (Box 18, Folder 200)
  - "T" general, 1914 Nov 12 (Box 18, Folder 201)
  - Ticknor, Benjamin H., 1887 (Box 18, Folder 202)
  - "V" general, 1900-09, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 203)
  - Van Dyke, Henry, 1898-1915 (Box 18, Folder 204)
  - "W" general, 1886-1909 (Box 18, Folder 205)
  - Warner, Charles Dudley, 1883-95 (Box 18, Folder 206)
  - Wood, Leonard, 1901-20 (Box 18, Folder 207)
  - Miscellaneous notes and autographs (Box 18, Folder 208)
  - Get-well letters, 1921-22 (Box 18, Folder 209)
  - Sympathy notes, 1922 (Box 18, Folder 210)
- Personal Papers, 1884-1961; Series IV; 1.0' (2 boxes)
  The Personal Papers of John Kendrick Bangs are arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Accounts
    - Harper and Brothers, 1893-1900 (Box 19, Folder 211-12)
    - Miscellaneous, 1897-1917 (Box 19, Folder 213-14)
  - American Committee for Devastated France, 1918, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 215)
  - Bangs, Nathan. ALS to Dr. and Mrs. Hibbard, 1856 Apr (Box 19, Folder 215a)
    With envelope, and calling card of Mrs. Lemuel Bangs.
  - Bibliography (J. K. Bangs titles), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 216)
  - Biographical information, 1884-1961 (Box 19, Folder 217-19)
  - Bookplate (copper plate), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 220)
  - Caricatures and cartoons (Box 19, Folder 221)
  - Diaries (schedules and accounts) (Box 19, Folder 222)
  - Lectures
    - Itinerary, 1921-22 (Box 20, Folder 223)
    - Announcements and reviews, 1903-21 (Box 20, Folder 224-26)
  - Life illustrations, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 227)
  - Merritt, Hal: illustrated postcard, 1904 (Box 20, Folder 228)
  - Mitchell, J. A.: original print, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 229)
  - Obituaries, 1922 (Box 20, Folder 230)
  - Portraits
    - Corfin, John, engraving of Bangs as Shakespeare, 1897 (Box 20, Folder 230a)
      With note by Corfin describing engraving and presenting it to Bangs
    - Newell, Peter, portrait of Bangs writing, tempera on fungus, mounted in glass and wood box (Box art, Folder 230b)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Restricted material. May not be seen without the permission of the appropriate curator.
  - Publicity material, 1895-1921, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 231-32)
  - Sterner, Albert. Sketches of John K. and Agnes Hyde Bangs, 1891, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 233)
  - Miscellaneous, 1902-17, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 234)
  - Printed Material
    - The Christian Advocate, 1926 September 9 (Box 61)
- Scrapbooks, 1913-64; Series V; 11.08' (27 boxes)
  The papers in Series V, Scrapbooks of Francis Hyde Bangs, are arranged chronologically.
  - Scrapbooks, 1913-15 (Box 21, Folder 235-37)
  - Scrapbooks, 1916-17 (Box 22, Folder 238-39)
  - Scrapbooks, 1917-19 (Box 23, Folder 240-41)
  - Scrapbooks, 1920 (Box 24, Folder 242)
  - Scrapbooks, 1921-22 (Box 25, Folder 243-44)
  - Scrapbooks, 1923-24 (Box 26, Folder 245-46)
  - Scrapbooks, 1925-26 (Box 27, Folder 247-48)
  - Scrapbooks, 1927-28 (Box 28, Folder 249-50)
  - Scrapbooks, 1929-30 (Box 29, Folder 251-52)
  - Scrapbooks, 1930-31 (Box 30, Folder 253-54)
  - Scrapbooks, 1932-33 (Box 31, Folder 255-56)
  - Scrapbooks, 1934-35 (Box 32, Folder 257-58)
  - Scrapbooks, 1936-38 (Box 33, Folder 259-61)
  - Scrapbooks, 1939-40 (Box 34, Folder 262-63)
  - Scrapbooks, 1941-42 (Box 35, Folder 264-65)
  - Scrapbooks, 1943-44 (Box 36, Folder 266-67)
  - Scrapbooks, 1945-46 (Box 37, Folder 268-69)
  - Scrapbooks, 1947 (Box 38, Folder 270-71)
  - Scrapbooks, 1949 (Box 39, Folder 272)
  - Scrapbooks, 1950 (Box 40, Folder 273-74)
  - Scrapbooks, 1951-52 (Box 41, Folder 275-76)
  - Scrapbooks, 1953-54 (Box 42, Folder 277-78)
  - Scrapbooks, 1955-56 (Box 43, Folder 279-80)
  - Scrapbooks, 1956-60 (Box 43a /folder 280a)
  - Scrapbooks, 1957-58 (Box 44, Folder 281-82)
  - Scrapbooks, 1959-60 (Box 45, Folder 283-84)
  - Scrapbooks, 1961-64 (Box 46, Folder 285-88)
- Writings, 1916-46; Series VI; 2.5' (6 boxes)
  Series VI, Writings, is divided into Books and Shorter Works, with an alphabetical arrangement by title. Under Shorter Works, Newspaper Articles and Letters to the Editor by Francis Hyde Bangs have been placed at the end of the series.
  - BOOKS
    - John Kendrick Bangs, Humorist of the Nineties
      - Research files
        - Genealogical information, 1916-35 (Box 47, Folder 289-91)
        - Poems: typescript copies, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 292)
        - Correspondence, 1928-46 (Box 47, Folder 293-95)